Guide to the Brander Matthews Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Brander Matthews Papers,
1877-1962.
Matthews, Brander, 1852-1929.
ca. 14,500 items (65 boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4078376
Biographical Note
Author, critic, and member of the Columbia English Department Faculty from 1891-1924. Matthews was an influential figure in the literary and dramatic worlds of New York and London from the 1880s throughtout his life. He was a member of numerous social and literary organizations, serving as president of the Dunlap Society, the Modern Language Association, and the National Institute of Arts and Letters, among others.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, documents, photographs, memorabilia, scrapbooks, and printed material. Among his correspondents represented in the collection by at least 75 items are: William Archer, Hobart C. Chatfield-Taylor, Augustin Daly, Austin Dobson, Hamlin Garland, Bronson Howard, William Dean Howells, Henry Arthur Jones, Henry Cabot Lodge and Thomas Raynesford Lounsbury. There are bound volumes of letters from Henry C. Bunner, Andrew Lang, Rudyard Kipling, Theodore Roosevelt, miscellaneous letters to Matthews, and Matthews' editorial correspondence with the North American Review. There are three boxes of manuscripts, including poems by 21 authors; essays on drama; and plays by Henry Arthur Jones, Don Marquis, and Matthews; bound volumes of manuscripts of Matthews' plays and his book, "Development for the Drama." Also included are 17 boxes of his manuscript notes for his many lectures, articles, and books; and memorabilia, primarily from the theatre and from his life at Columbia. Material on the Dunlap Society, which was devoted to printing works relating to the theater, of which Matthews was co-founder with Laurence Hutton, includes documents and correspondence, much of which is between then secretary Evert J. Wendell and members on meetings and other Society business around 1914. In addition, there are notes and correspondence of Herbert Kleinfield relating to his research on Matthews.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 6 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence, 1876-1926
Series II: Writings
Series III: Notes, 1872-1924
Series IV: Works by Others, 1879-1923
Series V: Personal files, 1827-1962
Series VI: Scrapbooks
Subjects
Columbia University.--Dept. of English and Comparative Literature.; Columbia University.--Dramatic Museum.; Archer, William, 1856-1924.; Bunner, H. C. (Henry Cuyler), 1855-1896.; Chatfield-Taylor, H. C. (Hobart Chatfield), 1865-1945.; Daly, Augustin, 1838-1899.; Dobson, Austin, 1840-1921.; Garland, Hamlin, 1860-1940.; Howard, Bronson, 1842-1908.; Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920.; Henderson, Harold Gould.; Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905.; Kelinfield, Herbert L.; Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936.; Jones, Henry Arthur, 1851-1929.; Lang, Andrew, 1844-1912.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924.; Lounsbury, Thomas Raynesford, 1838-1915.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Stoker, Bram, 1847-1912.; Theater--New York (State)--New York.; Theater--England--London.; American literature.; Photoprints
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
1912 Papers Matthews, Brander gift
1951 Biographical materials Henderson, Harold G. gift
1978 Biographical material Kleinfield, Jeanne Welcher gift
04/09/1993 M-93-04-09 Irving/Stoker a.l.s. to Rolt 6003B (B. Matthews) Purchase
03/09/1994 M-94-03-09 BM essay: On the length of Cleopatra's nose. 6003B (Matthews)-Auerbach Purchase
01/13/2000 M-00-01-13 16 a.l.s. from Matthews to Clifford Smyth Purchase
Alternate Formats
The Hamlin Garland letters (box 11) are on microfilm.
Gift of Brander Matthews, l9l2-1928; Harold G. Henderson, l951; and Jeanne Welcher Kleinfield, l978.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence, 1876-1926
  Matthews was an influential figure in the literary and dramatic worlds of New York, Paris, and London in the late nineteenth, early twentieth century. Among his correspondents represented in the collection are William Archer, Hobart C. Chatfield-Taylor, Augustin Daly, Austin Dobson, Hamlin Garland, Bronson Howard, William Dean Howells, Henry Cabot Lodge and other prominent figures from the worlds of theater, literature, politics and society. 10 linear ft.
  - Abbey, Edwin Austin (Box 1)
  - Abbey, Mary Gertrude (Mrs.E.A.) (Box 1)
  - Abdullah, Achmed (Box 1)
  - Abot, E (Box 1)
  - Adams, Charles Francis (Box 1)
  - Adams, Herbert (Box 1)
  - Ainger, Alfred (Box 1)
  - Alden, Henry Mills (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, Lilian Woodmsn (Mrs.T.B.) (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, Thomas Bailey (Box 1)
  - Alexander, John W. (Box 1)
  - Ames, Winthrop (Box 1)
  - Amory, Mathilda (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Edward Pretot (Box 1)
  - Anglin, Margaret (Box 1)
  - Appleton, George J. (Box 1)
  - Appleton, William Worthen (Box 1)
  - Archer, Charles (Box 1)
  - Archer, William (Box 1)
  - Arliss, George (Box 1 & 2)
  - Arrowsmith, J.W. (Box 2)
  - Ashby-Sterry, Joseph (Box 2)
  - Atherton, Gertrude (Box 2)
  - Aubert, Louis (Box 2)
  - Ayres, Harry Morgan (Box 2)
  - Bacheller, Irving (Box 2)
  - Baker, Franklin T. (Box 2)
  - Baker, George Pierce (Box 2)
  - Baldensperger, Fernand (Box 2)
  - Baldwin, Charles M. (Box 2)
  - Baldwin, Charles Sears (Box 2)
  - Balestier, Wolcott (Box 2)
  - Bangs, John Kendrick (Box 2)
  - Barnard,Charles (Box 2)
  - Barnard, Frederick Augustus Porter (Box 2)
  - Barr, Amelia Edith (Box 2)
  - Barrett, Lawrence (Box 2)
  - Bashford, G. Fred (Box 2)
  - Bassett, John D. (Box 2)
  - Bates, Blanche (Box 2)
  - Beckett., Harry (Box 2)
  - Beckwith, Carol (Box 2)
  - Beer, Thomas (Box 2)
  - Beers, Henry Augustin (Box 2)
  - Belasco, David (Box 2)
  - Bell, Edward Hamilton (Box 2)
  - Belmont, August (Box 2)
  - Belmont, Eleanor Robson (Box 2)
  - Benrimo, Joseph Henry McAlpin (Box 2)
  - Benson, Sir Francis Robert (Box 2)
  - Bernard, E.G. (Mrs. Wm. Bayle) (Box 2)
  - Besant, Mary (Box 2)
  - Besant, Walter (Box 2)
  - Bigelow, John (Box 2)
  - Bikle', Lucy Leffingwell Cable (Mrs. Henry Wolfe) (Box 2)
  - Bishop, Joseph Bucklin (Box 2)
  - Bishop, William Henry (Box 2)
  - Bispham, David (Box 2)
  - Blaikie, J.A. (Box 2)
  - Blashfield, Edwin Howland (Box 2)
  - Blinn, Holbrook (Box 2)
  - Bois, Jules (Box 2)
  - Bok, Edward W. (Box 2)
  - Booth, Agnes (Box 2)
  - Booth, Edwin (Box 2)
  - Bosworth, Hobart (Box 2)
  - Boucicault, Dion (Box 2)
  - Bourchier, Arthur (Box 2)
  - Boyeson, Hjalmar Hjorth (Box 2 & 3)
  - Bradford, Gamaliel (Box 3)
  - Bradley, Andrew Cecil (Box 3)
  - Brady, William A. (Box 3)
  - Brandes, George (Box 3)
  - Brewster, William Tenney (Box 3)
  - Bridges, Monica Waterhouse (Mrs.Robert) (Box 3)
  - Bridgman, Walter R. (Box 3)
  - Brieux, Eugene (Box 3)
  - Briggs, Alanson Tuthill (Box 3)
  - Brinton, Daniel Garrison (Box 3)
  - Broadhurst, Thomas W. (Box 3)
  - Brookfield, Jane Octavia (Mrs. Elton) (Box 3)
  - Brooks, Joseph (Box 3)
  - Brown, Henry (Box 3)
  - Brown, Henry Collins (Box 3)
  - Brownell, William Crarey (Box 3)
  - Brunetiere, Ferdinand (Box 3)
  - Brunner, Arnold W. (Box 3)
  - Bryce, James (Box 3)
  - Buel, Clarence Clough (Box 3)
  - Bunner, Henry Cuyler (Box 3)
    [See also 812M43S6, Scrapbook of Letters from H. C. Bunner]
  - Burlinghame, Edward Livermore (Box 3)
  - Burroughs, John(1837-1921) (Box 3)
  - Burton, Richard (Box 3)
  - Butcher, Samuel Henry (Box 3)
  - Butler, Benjamin (Box 3)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray (Box 3)
  - Cable,George Washington (Box 3)
  - Calkins, Ernest Elmo (Box 3)
  - Calvert, Louis (Box 3)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel (Box 3)
  - Carleton, Will (Box 3)
  - Carman, Bliss (Box 3)
  - Carnegie, Andrew (Box 3)
  - Carnegie, Mrs. Louis W. (Box 3)
  - Carr, Joseph William Comyns (Box 3)
  - Carvell, G.F. (Box 3)
  - Casey, Francis de Sales (Box 3)
  - Cawein, Madison (Box 3)
  - Chadwick, George Whitefield (Box 3)
  - Chambers, Sir Edmund Kerchever (Box 3)
  - Chambers, Raymond Wilson (Box 3)
  - Chandler, Frank Wadleigh (Box 3)
  - Chatfield-Taylor, Hobart Chatfield (Box 4)
  - Choate, Joseph H. (Box 4)
  - Church, William Conant (Box 4)
  - Churchill, Winston (Box 4)
  - Claretie, Jules (Box 4)
  - Clark, Joseph Ignatius Constantine (Box 4)
  - Claxton, Kate (Box 4)
  - Clemens., Olivia Langdon (Mrs. Samuel L.) (Box 4)
  - Clemens, Samuel L. (Box 4)
  - Cobb, Irvin S. (Box 4)
  - Coburn, Charles (Box 4)
  - Coghlan, Charles Francis (Box 4)
  - Coleman, John (Box 4)
  - Coles, J. Ackermn (Box 4)
  - Colvin, Sidney (Box 4)
  - Conkling, Roscoe (Box 4)
  - Conway, Hart (Box 4)
  - Conway, Martin (Box 4)
  - Conway, Moncure D. (Box 4)
  - Coogan, James J. (Box 4)
  - Coombes, George J. (Box 4)
  - Copeaux, Jacques (Box 4)
  - Coquelin, Benoit Constant (Box 4)
  - Corbin, John (Box 5)
  - Cortissoz, Royal (Box 5)
  - Cox, Kenyan (Box 5)
  - Coxon, Ethel (Box 5)
  - Crane, Ella Chloe Myers (Mrs.Wm.H.) (Box 5)
  - Crane, Stephen (Box 5)
  - Crane, William H. (Box 5)
  - Crawford, F. Marion (Box 5)
  - Crolly, C.C. (Box 5)
  - Crossman, Henrietta (Box 5)
  - Crothers, Samuel McChord (Box 5)
  - Curtis, Charles G. (Box 5)
  - Cushing, Charles P. (Box 5)
  - Dacre, Arthur (Box 5)
  - Daley, Augustin (Box 5)
  - Davenport, Eva (Box 5)
  - Davenport, Harry (Box 5)
  - Davis, Richard Harding (Box 5)
  - DeForest, John William (Box 5)
  - DeKay, Charles (Box 5)
  - deKoven, Reginald (Box 5)
  - DeMille, Anna George (Box 5)
  - DeMille, William C. (Box 5)
  - DeVinne, Theodore L. (Box 5)
  - Dickson, Frederick S. (Box 5)
  - Dillingham, Charles B (Box 5)
  - Dobson, Alban (Box 5)
  - Dobson, Austin (Box 5 & 6)
  - Dobson, Augusta-Mary Rachel (Box 6)
  - Dobson, Frances Mary Beardmore(Mrs. Austin) (Box 6)
  - Dodd, Mead & Co. (Box 6)
  - Dole, Nathan H. (Box 6)
  - Donnay, Maurice (Box 6)
  - Dow, David McKenzie (Box 6)
  - Drew, John (Box 6)
  - Drisler, Henry (Box 6)
  - Dufferin and Ava, Frederick Temple (Box 6)
  - Dyas, Ada (Box 6)
  - Eaton, Walter P. (Box 6)
  - Eddy, Frederick B. (Box 6)
  - Edson, C.L. (Box 6)
  - Edwards, Hy (Harry) (Box 6)
  - Egan, Maurice Francis (Box 6)
  - Eggleston, Edward (Box 6)
  - Eggleston, George Cary (Box 6)
  - Elliott, Maxine (Box 6)
  - English, Thomas Dunn (Box 6)
  - Ethel, Agnes (Box 6)
  - Faversham, William (Box 6)
  - Fawcett, Edgar (Box 6)
  - Felton, Cornelius Conway (Box 6)
  - Ferrar, John (Box 6)
  - Field, Eugene (Box 6)
  - Field, Kate (Box 6)
  - Field, Roswell Martin (Box 6)
  - Field, William B. Osgood (Box 6)
  - Finch, Francis Miles (Box 7)
  - Fish, Stuyvesant (Box 7)
  - Fiske, Minnie Maddern (Box 7)
  - Fitch, Clyde (Box 7)
  - Fitzmaurice-Kelly, James (Box 7)
  - Forbes-Robertson, Gertrude (Box 7)
  - Forbes-Robertson, Ian (Box 7)
  - Forbes-Robertson, Johnston (Box 7)
  - Ford, James L. (Box 7)
  - Ford, Mary (Box 7)
  - Ford, Paul Leicester (Box 7)
  - Fox, John, Jr. (Box 7)
  - Frantzius, Fritz von (Box 7)
  - Frawley, T. Daniel (Box 7)
  - French, Daniel Chester (Box 7)
  - French, Lillie Hamilton (Box 7)
  - French, Samuel (Box 7)
  - Frohman, Daniel (Box 7)
  - Furness, Horace Howard, Jr. (Box 7)
  - Garland, Hamlin (Box 7 & 8)
  - Garrison, Ella (Box 8)
  - Gayley, Charles Mills (Box 8)
  - George, Grace (Box 8)
  - George, Robert (Box 8)
  - Giddings, Franklin H. (Box 8)
  - Gilbert, Cass (Box 8)
  - Gilder, Helena deKay (Mrs.Rochard Watson) (Box 8)
  - Gilder, Jeannette L. (Box 8)
  - Gilder, Joseph B. (Box 8)
  - Gilder, Richard Watson (Box 8)
  - Giles, Peter (Box 8)
  - Gillette, William (Box 8)
  - Gilmare, Frank (Box 8)
  - Gilman, Charlotte Perkins Stetson (Box 8)
  - Gilman, Daniel Coit (Box 8)
  - Godfrey, Walter H. (Box 8)
  - Godkin, Edwin Lawrence (Box 8)
  - Godwin, Edward William (Box 8)
  - Godwin, Harold (Box 8)
  - Goodell, Thomas D. (Box 8)
  - Goodman, Jules Eckert (Box 8)
  - Goodwin, Nathaniel Carl (Box 8)
  - Gosse, Edmund (Box 8)
  - Gottheil, Richard (Box 8)
  - Grant, Robert (Box 8)
  - Granville-Baker, Harley (Box 8)
  - Graves, Henry (Box 8)
  - Gray, Agnes E. (Box 8)
  - Greene, Francis V. (Box 8)
  - Greenslet, Ferris (Box 8)
  - Greet, Ben (Box 8)
  - Grein, James Thomas (Box 8)
  - Grismer, Joseph Rhode (Box 8)
  - Grundy, Sydney (Box 8)
  - Guild, Thatcher Howland (Box 8)
  - Guiterman, Arthur (Box 8)
  - Guthrie, Anstey (Box 8)
  - Habberton, John (Box 8)
  - Hackett, James K (Box 8)
  - Hadley, Arthur Twi@ (Box 8)
  - Hagen, Claude L. (Box 8)
  - Haggard, Rider (Box 8)
  - Hake, Egmont A. (Box 8)
  - Hale, Edward Everett (Box 8)
  - Hall, Stanley G. (Box 8)
  - Hamilton, Clayton (Box 8 & 9)
  - Hampden, Walter (Box 9)
  - Hankin, St. John (Box 9)
  - Hanlon, George (Box 9)
  - Hapgood, Norman (Box 9)
  - Harle, Hugh C. (Box 9)
  - Harper, Joseph Henry (Box 9)
  - Harrigan, Edward (Box 9)
  - Harrigan, Mrs. Edward (Box 9)
  - Harris, Joel Chandler (Box 9)
  - Hart, Albert Bushnell (Box 9)
  - Hartmann, Sadakichi (Box 9)
  - Harvey, George Brinton McClellan (Box 9)
  - Hastings, Thomas (Box 9)
  - Hazleton, George C. (Box 9)
  - Henley, William Ernest (Box 9)
  - Herfor, Oliver (Box 9)
  - Herrick, Robert (Box 9)
  - Hibbard, George (Box 9)
  - Hibben, John Grier (Box 9)
  - Higginson, Margaret W. (Box 9)
  - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth (Box 9)
  - Hinman, Russell (Box 9)
  - Hitchcock, Ripley (Box 9)
  - Holland, David B. (Box 9)
  - Holland, E.M. (Box 9)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell (Box 9)
  - Holt, Henry (Box 9)
  - Hood, William (Box 9)
  - Hooker, Brian (Box 9)
  - Houdini, Harry (Box 9)
  - Howard, Bronson (Box 10)
  - Howard, Sidney (Box 10)
  - Howe, Edgar Watson (Box 10)
  - Howe, Julia Ward (Box 10)
  - Howells, John Mead (Box 10)
  - Howells, Mildred (Box 10)
  - Hoyt, Charles (Box 10)
  - Howells, William Dean (Box 10 & 11)
  - Hughes, Rupert (Box 11)
  - Humphreys, Alex C. (Box 11)
  - Huneker, James Gordon (Box 11)
  - Hunt, T.F. (Box 11)
  - Hunt, William (Box 11)
  - Huntington, Archer M. (Box 11)
  - Hutchinson, Thomas (Box 11)
  - Hutton, Eleanor V. (Box 11)
  - Hutton, Lawrence (Box 11)
  - Ingersoll, Ernest (Box 11)
  - Ingersoll, William (Box 11)
  - Ireland, Alexander (Box 11)
  - Ireland, Joseph N. (Box 11)
  - Irving, Henry (Box 11)
  - Irving, Lawrence (Box 11)
  - Irwin, Wallace (Box 11)
  - Irwin, Will (Box 11)
  - Jagemann, Hans Carl Gunter von (Box 11)
  - James, Henry (Box 11)
  - James, Louis L. (Box 11)
  - Janvier, Catharine A. (Box 11)
  - Jerome, William T. (Box 11)
  - Jesperson, Otto (Box 11)
  - Jessop, George H. (Box 11)
  - Jewett, Sara (Box 11)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood (Box 11)
  - Johnson, Rossiter (Box 11)
  - Johnson, Willard D. (Box 11)
  - Jones, Henry Arthur (Box 11 & 12)
  - Jones, Richard (Box 12)
  - Jones, Robert Edmund (Box 12)
  - Jusserand, Jean Jules (Box 12)
  - Keep, Elizabeth (Box 12)
  - Keppel, Frederick P. (Box 12)
  - Kester., Paul (Box 12)
  - Kimball, Arthur R. (Box 12)
  - Kinnaird, Arthur Fitzgerald (Box 12)
  - Kipling, Caroline (Mrs. Rudyard) (Box 12)
  - Kipling, Elsie (Box 12)
  - Kipling, Rudyard (Box 12)
  - Kirk, John Foster (Box 13)
  - Klaw, Marc (Box 13)
  - Klein, Charles (Box 13)
  - Kure, B. (Box 13)
  - LaFarge, John (Box 13)
  - LaFollette, Robert (Box 13)
  - Lampton, William J. (Box 13)
  - Lang, Andrew (Box 13)
  - Lanigan, George Thomas (Box 13)
  - Lanson, Gustave (Box 13)
  - Lathrop, George Parsons (Box 13)
  - Lawrence, William John (Box 13)
  - Lawrence, William Witherle (Box 13)
  - Learned, Walter (Box 13)
  - Lee, Sidney (Box 13)
  - Lefevre, Edwin (Box 13)
  - LeGallienne, Richard (Box 13)
  - LeMoyne, Sarah Cowell (Box 13)
  - Lewis, James (Box 13)
  - Locker-Lampson, Frederick (Box 13)
  - Locker-Lampson, Hannah Jane (Box 13)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot (1850-1924) (Box 13 & 14)
  - Loftie, William John (Box 14)
  - Logan, Celia (Box 14)
  - Long, John L. (Box 14)
  - Longman, Charles James (Box 14)
  - Longmans, Green & Co. (Box 14)
  - Lounsbury, Thomas Raynesford (Box 14)
  - Low, Seth (Box 14 & 15)
  - Lowe, Robert A. (Box 15)
  - Lowell, A Lawrence (Box 15)
  - Lowell, Sydney (Box 15)
  - Ludemann, Alfred (Box 15)
  - Lummis, Charles F. (Box 15)
  - Mabie, Hamilton Wright (Box 15)
  - Macalister, Donald (Box 15)
  - McCutcheon, George Barr (Box 15)
  - McClellan, George Brinton (Box 15)
  - MacDowell, Edward (Box 15)
  - McDowell, Henry Barden (Box 15)
  - McIlvaine, Clarence W. (Box 15)
  - MacKay, Clarence H. (Box 15)
  - Mackay, Frank F. (Box 15)
  - MacKaye, Percy (Box 15)
  - McMahon, Una (Box 15)
  - McMaster, John B. (Box 15)
  - McVicker, J.H. (Box 15)
  - Magnus, Julian (Box 15)
  - Magruder, Julia (Box 15)
  - Mahan, Alfred Thayer (Box 15)
  - Malevinsky, Moses L. (Box 15)
  - Malone, John T. (Box 15)
  - Manley, John M. (Box 15)
  - Mantle, Burns (Box 15)
  - Mantzius, Karl (Box 15)
  - Marbury, Elizabeth (Box 15)
  - Marks, Stacy H. (Box 15)
  - Marquis, Don (Box 15)
  - Marshall, Henry R. (Box 15)
  - Martin, Edward Sandford (Box 15)
  - Martin-Harvey, John (Box 15)
  - Massenet, Jules (Box 15)
  - Masson, Frederick (Box 15)
  - Masson, Thomas L. (Box 15)
  - Matthews, Ada S. (Mrs. Brander) (Box 15)
  - Matthews, Brander (Box 15 & 16)
  - Matthews, Edith V. Brander (Box 16)
  - Maurice, Arthur Bartlett (Box 16)
  - Maxim, Hudson (Box 16)
  - Mayfield, John S. (Box 16)
  - Mayo, Frank (Box 16)
  - Meeks, Raymond (Box 16)
  - Mencken, Henry Louis (Box 16)
  - Merrill, Stuart (Box 16)
  - Merwin, Samuel (Box 16)
  - Meyer, Paul (Box 16)
  - Meynall, Percy (Box 16)
  - Middleton, George (Box 16)
  - Miller, Henry (Box 16)
  - Millet, Francis Davis (Box 16)
  - Mitchell, Grant (Box 16)
  - Mitchell, John Ames (Box 16)
  - Mitchell, Langdon E. (Box 16)
  - Mitchell, Silas Weir (Box 16)
  - Moderwell, Hiram Kelly (Box 16)
  - Modjeska, Helena (Box 16)
  - Monkhouse, Cosmo (Box 16)
  - Monval, Leon (Box 16)
  - Morange, Edward A. (Box 16)
  - Morazzoni, Giuseppe (Box 16)
  - More, Paul E. (Box 16)
  - Morford, Henry (Box 16)
  - Morley, Christopher (Box 16)
  - Morris, Lloyd R. (Box 16)
  - Morrison, Charlotte (Box 16)
  - Morrison, Lewis (Box 16)
  - Moses, Montrose J. (Box 16)
  - Mulholland, John (Box 16)
  - Munroe, Kirk (Box 16)
  - Munsey, Frank A. (Box 16)
  - Murray, Gilbert (Box 16)
  - Murray, John (Box 16)
  - Nakamura, Kichizo (Box 16)
  - Nast, Thomas (Box 16)
  - Neill, James (Box 16)
  - Nelson, (Miss) F. E. (Box 16)
  - Nelson, Henry Loomis (Box 16)
  - Neville, Henry Gartside (Box 16)
  - Newbolt, Henry (Box 16)
  - Newcomer, Alice K. (Box 16)
  - Nicholson, Meredith (Box 16)
  - Noguchi, Yone (Box 16)
  - Norcross, John E. (Box 16)
  - Norman, Henry (Box 16)
  - Olin, Reeves and Montgomery (Box 16)
  - Opper, Frederick Burr (Box 16)
  - Omonde, Eugene (Box 16)
  - Osgood, James Ripley (Box 16)
  - Owen, William F. (Box 16)
  - Owens, John E. (Box 16)
  - Ozawa Yoshikuni (Box 16)
  - Page, L.C. & Co. (Box 16)
  - Page, Thomas Nelson (Box 16)
  - Page, Walter (Box 16)
  - Paine, Albert Bigelow (Box 16)
  - Palmer, Albert Marshman (Box 16)
  - Palmer, Courtlandt (Box 16)
  - Palmer, Frederick (Box 16)
  - Parker, Gilbert (Box 16)
  - Parker Henry Taylor (Box 16)
  - Parker, Horatio (Box 16)
  - Parlow, Kathleen (Box 16)
  - Payne, John (Box 16)
  - Payne, Will (Box 16)
  - Peck, Harry Thurston (Box 16)
  - Penfield, Edward (Box 16)
  - Pennell, Elizabeth Robins (Box 16)
  - Perry, Bliss (Box 16)
  - Phelps, William Lyon (Box 16 & 17)
  - Pinero, Arthur Wing (Box 17)
  - Pinker, James B. (Box 17)
  - Polk, William Mecklenburg (Box 17)
  - Pollock, Channing (Box 17)
  - Pollock, Sir Francis (Box 17)
  - Pollock, Walter H. (Box 17)
  - Pool, Frank J. (Box 17)
  - Porter, Fitz John (Box 17)
  - Porter, Horace (Box 17)
  - Post, Louis F. (Box 17)
  - Potter, Henry Codman (Box 17)
  - Potter, Paul Meredith (Box 17)
  - Pound, Ezra (Box 17)
  - Presbrey, Eugene W. (Box 17)
  - Price, Thomas R. (Box 17)
  - Putnam, George Haven (Box 17)
  - Putnam, Irving (Box 17)
  - Pyle, Howard (Box 17)
  - Radin, Herman G. (Box 17)
  - Rae, William Fraser (Box 17)
  - Randall, James Ryder (Box 17)
  - Raymond, John T. (Box 17)
  - Reed. Roland (Box 17)
  - Remington, Frederic (Box 17)
  - Rennert, Hugo A. (Box 17)
  - Repplier, Agnes (Box 17)
  - Rhodes, James F. (Box 17)
  - Rice, Cale Young (Box 17)
  - Rice, Wallace (Box 17)
  - Richards, Grant (Box 17)
  - Riggs, Arthur Stanley (Box 17)
  - Riggs, Mrs. Kate (Box 17)
  - Roberts, Morley (Box 17)
  - Robson, Stuart (Box 17)
  - Roosevelt, Edith Kermit (Box 17)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 17)
  - Rosenfeld, Sydney (Box 17)
  - Rosenthal, Ludwig (Box 17)
  - Royce, Joseph (Box 17)
  - Ruckstull, Fred Wallinton (Box 17)
  - Russell-Yorke, Annie (Box 17)
  - Russell, Sol Smith (Box 17)
  - Sadler, Sir Michael Ernest (Box 17)
  - Saintsbury, George (Box 17)
  - Saltus, Edgar (Box 17)
  - Saltus, Francis S. (Box 17)
  - Sangster, Margaret Elizabeth (Box 17)
  - Sarasate y Navasues, Pablo Martin Melitonde (Box 17)
  - Sarcey, Francisque (Box 17)
  - Schauffler, Robert Haven (Box 17)
  - Schertz, Helen Pitkin (Box 17)
  - Schoepel, Agnes (Box 18)
  - Scollard, Clinton (Box 18)
  - Scott, Fred Newton (Box 18)
  - Scribner, Charles (Box 18)
  - Sedgwick, Henry Dwight (Box 18)
  - Sedgwick, William T. (Box 18)
  - Seymour, William (Box 18)
  - Shackleford, John (Box 18)
  - Sheffauer Herman George (Box 18)
  - Sheridan Richard Brinsley (1809-88) (Box 18)
  - Sherman, Frank Dempster (Box 18)
  - Sherman, Stuart P. (Box 18)
  - Shipman, Louis (Box 18)
  - Shorey, Paul (Box 18)
  - Simms, Edward (Box 18)
  - Skinner, Otis (Box 18)
  - Sladen, Douglas (Box 18)
  - Sloane, William Milligan (Box 18)
  - Smith, C. Alphonso (Box 18)
  - Smith, Logan Pearsall (Box 18)
  - Smith, Munroe (Box 18)
  - Snyder, Frank M. (Box 18)
  - Sousa, John Philip (Box 18)
  - Spingarn, Joel Ellis (Box 18)
  - Stanford, Sir Charles Villiers (Box 18)
  - Stedman, Edmund Clarence (Box 18)
  - Stedman, Laura (Box 18)
  - Stimson, Frederick Jessop (Box 18)
  - Stockton, Francis Richard (Box 18)
  - Stoddard, Charles Warren (Box 18)
  - Stoddard, Francis Hovey (Box 18)
  - Stoker, Bram (Box 18)
  - Story, William Westmore (Box 18)
  - Stratton-Porter, Gene (Box 18)
  - Street, Julian (Box 18)
  - Sturges, Jonathan (Box 18)
  - Sturgis, Russell (Box 18)
  - Sutro, Alfred (Box 18)
  - Symons, Arthur (Box 18)
  - Taber, Robert (Box 18)
  - Tedder., Henry Richard (Box 18)
  - Terhune, Albert Payson (Box 18)
  - Terhune,, Mary Virginia (Hawes) (Box 18)
  - Thayer, William R. (Box 18 & 19)
  - Thomas, A. E. (Box 19)
  - Thomas, Augustus (Box 19)
  - Thompson, Henry (Box 19)
  - Thorndike, Ashley Horace (Box 19)
  - Thorne, Charles R., Jr. (Box 19)
  - Ticknor, Benjamin H. (Box 19)
  - Tilley, Arthur (Box 19)
  - Titherington, Richard Handsfield (Box 19)
  - Tourgee, Aimee (Box 19)
  - Townsend, Horace (Box 19)
  - Towse, John Ranken (Box 19)
  - Tree, H. Beerbohm (Box 19)
  - Trent, William (Box 19)
  - Twichell, Joseph M. (Box 19)
  - Tyler, Moses Coit (Box 19)
  - Unwin, T. Fisher (Box 19)
  - Van Dyke, Henry (Box 19)
  - Van Dyke, John Charles (Box 19)
  - Vedder, Elihu (Box 19)
  - Vezin, Hermann (Box 19)
  - Viele, Herman Knickerbocker (Box 19)
  - Villard, Henry (Box 19)
  - Waddington, Samuel (Box 19)
  - Walker, Alfred (Box 19)
  - Walkley, Arthur Bingham (Box 19)
  - Wallack, Arthur (Box 19)
  - Wallack, Lester (Box 19)
  - Ward, Adolphus William (Box 19)
  - Ward, Fannie Batchelder (Mrs. C. Montagu) (Box 19)
  - Ware, Helen (Box 19)
  - Warfield, David (Box 19)
  - Warner, Charles Dudley (Box 19)
  - Warner, John E. (Box 19)
  - Watson, Henry Brereton Marriott (Box 19)
  - Welcker, Adair (Box 19)
  - Wells, Carolyn (Box 19)
  - Wendell, Barrett (Box 19)
  - Wendell, Evert Jansen (Box 19)
  - Westerfield, Paul (Box 19)
  - Wheeler, Benjamin Ide (Box 19)
  - Whiffen, Blanche (Box 19)
  - Whiffen, Thomas (Box 19)
  - White, Andrew D. (Box 20)
  - White, Gleason (Box 20)
  - White, J. William (Box 20)